《行尸走肉》
15点方向  你去放哨
15, you're on point.
我们没地方可去了
We got no place left to go.
如果这两个僵尸群相遇  我们就完蛋了
When this herd meets up with this one, we'll be cut off.
绝对去不了南边
We'll never make it south.
怎么办  那群大概有150只吧
What would you say? That was about 150 head?
那还是上周  现在可能已经翻倍了
That was last week. It could be twice that by now.
这条河能拖延它们
This river could have delayed them.
如果动作快
If we move fast,
我们也许能从这穿过去
we might have a shot to tear right through there.
但如果那两群合并了
Yeah, but if this group joins with that one,
他们就可能从这条路蜂拥而来
They could spill out this way.
就是说我们被挡住去路了
So we're blocked.
现在只能再回27区
Only thing to do is double back at 27
从那儿去格林维尔
and swing towards Greenville.
我们去过那儿了
Yeah, we picked through that already.
好像整个冬天我们都在不停绕圈子
It's like we spent the winter going in circles.
我知道
Yeah, I know. I know.
从纽南向西走
At Newnan we'll push west.
那里还没去过
Haven't been through there yet.
我们不能一直四处奔波
We can't keep going house to house.
必须找到个能安全过几周的地方
Need to find someplace to hole up for a few weeks.
好吧  出发前我们能
All right. Is it cool if we get to the creek
先去趟河边吗  不会很久
before we head out? Won't take long.
得去装水  一会煮沸
We got to fill up on water. We can boil it later.
随便
Knock yourself out.
她不能再这么奔波了
She can't take much more of this moving about.
能怎么办  让她在逃亡中生产吗
What else can we do? Let her give birth on the run?
恐怕没别的选择了
Do you see a way around that?
趁他们洗裤子
Hey, while the others wash their panties,
咱们打猎去
let's go hunt.
一只猫头鹰可满足不了大家
That owl didn't exactly hit the spot.
真可惜
That's a shame.
-当心背后  -知道
- Watch the backside. - Got it.
快点  快
Hurry. Hurry!
这真棒
It's perfect.
要是能关上那门
If we can shut that gate,
以防更多的进来
prevent more from filling the yard,
我们就能解决这些行尸
we can pick off these walkers.
晚上就能拿下这块空地了
We'll take the field by tonight.
该怎么关门呢
So how do we shut the gate?
我去  你们掩护我
I'll do it. You guys cover me.
不行  这简直是自杀
No. It's a suicide run.
我速度最快
I'm the fastest.
不  你  玛姬和贝丝去那边尽量引它们注意
No, you, Maggie, and Beth draw as many as you can over there.
从栅栏后捅它们
Pop 'em through the fence.
达里尔  去那边的塔
Daryl, go back to the other tower.
卡萝尔  你枪法越来越好了
Carol, you've become a pretty good shot.
仔细瞄准  别浪费子弹
Take your time. We don't have a lot of ammo to waste.
赫谢尔  你和卡尔上这座塔
Hershel, you and Carl take this tower.
我去关门
I'll run for the gate.
-过来  -有种过来
- Come on! - Hey, come here!
-来啊  -来这啊
过来  来啊
Come on! Come on!
过来  过来
抱歉
Sorry.
过来  这里
Hey, come on, over here!
快来这边
Hey, hey, hey! Come on, over here!
他成功了
He did it.
好样的
Light it up!
太爽了
Fansticing
射得漂亮
Nice shooting.
你还好吗
You okay?
几周来最舒坦的一次
I haven't felt this good in weeks.
太好了
Good.
离开农场后  好久没见这么广阔的地方了
We haven't had this much space since we left the farm.
就像妈妈亲手做的味道
Mmm. Just like mom used to make.
明天我们把所有尸体聚到一起
Tomorrow we'll put all the bodies together.
让它们远离水源
Want to keep them away from that water.
如果我们在铁栏下挖一条渠
Now, if we can dig a canal under the fence,
就能引来新鲜水源
we'll have plenty of fresh water.
土壤不错
And the soil is good,
我们可以撒下种子
we can plant some seeds.
种一些番茄  黄瓜  黄豆
Grow some tomatoes, cucumbers, soybeans.
他已经检查三圈了
That's his third time around.
如果铁栏有漏洞
If there was any part of it compromised,
他一定会发现的
he'd have found it by now.
这是个待产的好地方
This'll be a good place to have the baby.
安全
Safe.
虽然不多  但如果我不给你带点儿
It's not much, but if I don't bring you something,
你压根就不会吃
you won't eat at all.
我猜她肚里的小肖恩食欲也不错吧
I guess little Shane over there has got quite the appetite.
别这么毒舌
Don't be mean.
瑞克比我预期的带我们走了更远
Rick's gotten us a lot farther than I ever thought he would,
这点不可否认
I'll give him that.
肖恩就做不到
Shane could never have done that.
怎么了
What's wrong?
是步枪  后座力太大
It's that rifle. The kickback.
我不太习惯
I'm just not used to it.
等一下
Hold on.
你还是回去吧
Better get back.
今夜浪漫满屋
It's pretty romantic.
顺便来一发吧
Want to screw around?
我去下面了
I'll go down first.
那更好
Even better.
别扯了
Stop.
贝丝  给我唱那首帕迪·雷利的歌吧
Bethy, sing Paddy Reilly for me.
自从你妈妈离世后
I haven't heard that, I think,
就再没有听过了
since your mother was alive.
爸爸  求你别让她唱那首
Daddy, not that one, please.
一首凯尔特民谣
那就唱《离别的酒杯》吧
How about "Parting Glass"?
没人想听
No one wants to hear.
唱吧
Why not?
好吧
Okay.
真动听
Beautiful.
你们最好都睡一觉
Better all turn in.
我来守夜
I'll take watch over there.
明天还有大事要做
Got a big day tomorrow.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我知道大家都筋疲力尽了
Look, I know we're all exhausted.
今天我们赢得漂亮
This was a great win.
但是我们还得再努力一下
But we've got to push just a little bit more.
大部分行尸都穿着守卫和囚犯的衣服
Most of the walkers are dressed as guards and prisoners.
看起来这个地方很早就沦陷了
Looks like this place fell pretty early.
也就意味着供应品可能会很充足
It could mean the supplies may be intact.
监狱一般会有医务室
They'd have an infirmary,
还有食堂
a commissary.
有军械库吗
An armory?
军械库单独建在监狱外
That would be outside the prison itself,
但也不会太远
but not too far away.
狱长办公室里应该会有军械库的位置信息
Warden's offices would have info on the location.
武器  食物  药品
Weapons, food, medicine.
这个地方可能是个大金矿
This place could be a gold mine.
我们的弹药太少了
We're dangerously low on ammo.
杀不了几个就会用完
We'd run out before we make a dent.
所以我们要进去
That's why we have to go in there...
近身肉搏
hand to hand.
我们一起经历了那么多事情
After all we've been through,
我们能赢的  我有信心
we can handle it. I know it.
这帮混球死定了
These assholes don't stand a chance.
我感谢你所做的一切
I appreciate everything you're doing.
我们都非常感谢
we all do,
但是行尸那么多  大家都精疲力尽了
but it's been a death March and they're exhausted.
我们不能先休息几天吗
Can we just enjoy this for a few days?
宝宝过些日子就要出世了
Baby will be here in a few days.
没有时间来玩野餐
There's no time for a picnic.
对  但是我们应该先找好住处
No, but it's time to get the house in order.
你以为我在做什么
What do you think I'm doing?
你是最有能力的
You're absolute best.
别对我居高临下说话
Don't patronize me.
我没有
I'm not.
我只是想说
I'm just saying
宝宝就快出世了
the baby is about to be here
-我们需要谈谈  -谈什么
- and we need to talk about-- - About what?
我们一直逃避的事情
Things we've been avoiding--
你想要谈谈  那就去和赫谢尔谈吧
You want to talk? Talk to Hershel.
我在做事  洛莉
I'm doing stuff, Lori.
还"谈事情"  事还不够多吗
"Things." Isn't that enough?
我还在这
I'm still here.
你说得对
You're right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
准备好了吗
Ready?
达里尔
Daryl.
来吧
Come on.
靠拢  靠拢
Get tight! Get tight!
-过来  来这  -这边
- Come on, over here! - Hey! Over here!
过来  来这边
Come on, over here!
-不要打乱队形  -我们需要那个
- Don't break rank! - We need that.
T仔  T仔
T! T!
玛姬  玛姬
Maggie! Maggie!
快到了
Almost there.
见鬼
Shit.
我看不到他们 你能看见吗
I can't see them. Can you see them?
在后面吗
Back there?
达里尔
Daryl!
-快点  -好了
- Come on. - We're good.
看到了吗
See that?
停一下
Stop.
看起来很安全
Well, it looks secure.
那边的院子看起来可不安全
Not from the look of that courtyard over there.
那是个平民
And that's a civilian.
所以监狱里可能到处都是
So the interior could be overrun with walkers
从外面涌进来的行尸
from outside the prison.
如果哪里破开了  我们怎么办
Well, if there's walls down, what are we gonna do?
总不能重新开拓建这个地方吧
We can't rebuild this whole place.
不能有盲点
We can't risk a blind spot.
我们必须继续往里去
We have to push in.
你觉得如何
What do you think?
回家真好
Home sweet home.
眼下已经很不错了
For the time being.
这里安全吗
It's secure?
这个单元区安全
This cellblock is.
监狱其他部分呢
What about the rest of the prison?
明早我们就去找餐厅和医务室
In the morning, we'll find the cafeteria and infirmary.
我们在监狱里睡吗
We sleep in the cells?
我在狱吏那找到钥匙  达里尔也有一套
I found keys on some guards. Daryl has a set, too.
我才不睡在笼子里
I ain't sleeping in no cage.
我去上面睡
I'll take the perch.
来吧
Come on.
谢谢你
Thank you.
真恶心
Pretty gross.
还记得那个储藏室吗
Yeah, remember the storage units?
其实  其实挺舒服的
It's actually-- it's actually comfortable.
试试看
Check it out.
找到你的房间了吗
You find your cell yet?
我只想  只想把贝丝安顿好
Yeah. Just ah… just want Beth to sleep.
-明天见  -明天见
- See you tomorrow. - See you.
我实在精疲力尽了  我不管了
I'm so exhausted, I don't even care.
来  我看看
Here, let me see.
你在干什么
What're you doing?
看看有没有擦伤
Checking for scratches.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing out here?
我需要点光
I needed some light.
喝水
Take this.
外面情况怎么样
How is it out there?
还那样
Same.
太静了
It's quiet.
你撒谎
You're lying.
我们几天后就得出发
We should go in a few days.
他们要来了
They're coming.
-你得赶快走  -不行
- You should go. - No.
我会拖你后腿的  走吧
I'll hold you back. Go.
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself.
我整个冬天都在救你的小命  不是吗
I saved your ass all winter, didn't I?
我才不要你为我丧命
I won't have you dying for me.
好兵不弃岗
Good soldier won't leave your post.
去你的吧
Screw you.
我们过几天就离开这里
We'll go in a few days.
如果我们待在这儿
If we stay...
我会死在这里
I'll die here.
还不错
Not bad.
闪光弹  强力手雷
Flashbangs, CS triple-chasers.
不知道对行尸管不管用
Not sure how they'd work on walkers,
但是还是带上吧
but we'll take 'em.
我才不穿这鬼东西
I ain't wearing this shit.
可以开水消毒
We could boil 'em.
林子里可没那么多树可以烧  得了吧
Ain't enough firewood in the whole forest. No.
还有  我们没穿这些也一路走过来了
Besides, we made it this far without 'em, right?
赫谢尔
Hershel.
没什么事吧
Everything all right?
没事  没什么好担心的
Yeah. Nothing to worry about.
是肚子里的孩子  我觉得保不住
It's the baby. I think I lost it.
-你感觉不到胎动吗  -丝毫没有
- You haven't felt it move? - Nothing.
也没有宫缩
And no Braxton-Hicks.
开始我以为是疲劳或营养不良的原因
At first I thought it was exhaustion or malnutrition.
你贫血吗
You're anemic?
如果我们都感染了  那这孩子也一样
If we're all infected, then so's the baby.
要是孩子是死胎呢
So what if it's stillborn?
要是已经胎死腹中怎么办
What if it's dead inside me right now?
-要是子宫撕裂怎么办  -停下
- What if it rips me apart… - Stop.
别让恐惧占据你的内心
Don't let your fear take control of you.
好
Okay.
假设孩子活下来  而我死于分娩
Then let's say it lives and I die during childbirth.
-那不会发生的  -怎么不会
- That's not going to happen. - Why not?
现代医疗时代以前  很多女人都死于分娩
How many women died in childbirth before modern medicine?
如果我再活过来
If I come back,
攻击孩子呢
what if I attack it?
攻击你  或者瑞克呢
Or you? Or Rick?
或者卡尔
Or Carl?
如果万一那样
If I do, if there is any chance,
你就立刻杀了我
you put me down immediately.
如果我和孩子都是行尸  不要犹豫
You don't hesitate. Me, the baby,
杀了我们
if we're walkers,
别犹豫  别试着救我们
You don't hesitate and you don't try to save us.
好吗
Okay?
本能更好的  如果...
It might have been better if--
什么意思
If what?
如果我没逃出农场的话
I'd never made it off the farm.
你累了  被吓到了
You're exhausted, frightened.
是啊  没错
Yeah, that's true.
我儿子嫌我烦
My son can't stand me.
我丈夫经过那件事后
And my husband, after what I put him through...
我们都在为那件事难受
We've all been carrying that weight
整个冬天都是
all winter.
我试着跟他好好说话
I tried to talk to him.
但他...
He...
他会想通的
He'll come around.
他恨我
He hates me.
他虽然不忍心说  但我明白
He's too good a man to say it, but I know.
我离间了他和肖恩  我令他成为了杀手
I put him and Shane at odds. I put that knife in his hand.
你知道谁不在乎这些屁事吗
You know who doesn't give a shit about that?
这个孩子不在乎
This baby.
让我们确保一切都好起来吧
Now let's make sure everything's all right.
你用不上那个
You won't need that.
我需要你留在这里
I need you to stay put.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding?
我们不知道里面什么情况
We don't know what's in there.
如果我们遭遇不测  你就是最后一个男子汉
Something goes wrong, you could be the last man standing.
我需要你在这里管事
I need you to handle things here.
没问题
Sure.
很好  我们走
Great. Let's go.
抱歉
Sorry.
-往回走  快  -有行尸
- Go back. Go back! Move! - Walkers!
这边
This way.
进去
In here!
-格伦和玛姬呢  -我们必须回去
- Where's Glenn and Maggie? - We have to go back.
可走哪条路呢
But which way?
玛姬  格伦
Maggie? Glenn?
-瑞克  -爸爸
- Rick? - Dad?
爸爸
Daddy?
玛姬
Mag?
不
No!
-不  -玛姬
- No! - Maggie!
爸爸  不
Daddy, no!
-达里尔  -天啊  帮帮我
- Daryl! - Oh, god, help me!
-格伦  -我们被堵住了  快回去
- Glenn! - We're blocked! Get back! Get back!
快  快
Go! Go!
把门打开
Open the door!
进去
Get in!
关上门
Shut the door!
门堵住了吗
You got it? Have you got it?
快点
Hurry up!
按住他
Hold him down.
只有一个办法能救你
Only one way to keep you alive.
他失血很多
He's bleeding out.
蹲下
Duck.
卧槽
Holyshit!